# **Adam Hoar**

Mob: 07584573146 Email: adam.hoar@icloud.com





#### **PROFILE**

Software Engineering Bootcamp Graduate, originally with a background in Asset Management and Startups. As a Full Stack Developer I get to do the things I genuinely enjoy; solving tough problems with creative solutions, being part of a team that works to build amazing things and constantly learning as I go.

Prior to joining Makers I was employee #4 at a <u>successful Health Care startup</u> where I gained first hand experience in Agile methodologies. Additionally, I developed as a leader over time, ultimately managing a large team of people both in the field and in person. Key to our collective success was communication, adapting quickly to new situations, learning from our mistakes and executing on our long term vision.

One of our achievements: LaingBuisson Award for Innovation.

### **PROJECTS**

<u>Destination Unknown</u> (Full Stack) - Javascript, React, Node, Express, HTML & CSS - TDD with Jest & Cypress

- A travel destination comparison site. Features include flight prices, budget, safety and accommodation comparison.
- A Test Driven programme developed with Agile, daily stand-ups, retros and sprints.

Acebook (Full Stack) - MongoDB, Express, React, Node - TDD with Jest & Cypress

- A social media app that allows users to register/log in, post, edit their posts, comment on posts, like posts, delete posts and add friends.
- Built using Agile over 3 sprints covering 10 days.

Sent-ence-iment (Full Stack) - Javascript, Python, Flask, React, NLTK

- A Machine Learning Natural language Processing app that can gauge the positivity/negativity of a phrase provided by the user.
- Check out the deployed site and have a go yourself here.

## **EXPERIENCE**

### Software Engineering Student, Makers Academy

November 2022 - March 2023

- Makers is an intensive 4 month bootcamp created and run by industry leading engineers.
   Producing language agnostic, self-sufficient software engineers.
- Learnt key concepts such as Test Driven Development, Object Oriented Programming, Agile and REST APIs. This was taught in conjunction with Full Stack Development using Javascript, React, Node, Ruby, PostgreSQL and Python.
- Working to tight time frames we completed a range of individual, paired programming and team work.
- An extensive El curriculum focusing on teamwork, empathy and feedback in a technical environment.

## Director/Co-Owner, Roland Bailey Imports US

July 2020 - July 2022

- Created a company that sourced classic cars in the U.K, shipped them to the US and sold them.
- Generated over \$50,000 revenue in our first 12 months trading.
- Used our initiative to overcome large logistical and regulatory hurdles to ship the cars ourselves, reducing costs by thousands per vehicle.

 As the economic cost of covid lingered with regards to container shipping costs, parts manufacturing delays and the general economic downturn we made the hard decision to stop the business.

#### **Operations Manager, Lifted**

March 2020 - November 2021

- Streamlined business operations and improved inter-team collaboration by implementing new systems and processes. For example, creating a new Recruitment Funnel that cut candidate processing time from 2/3 weeks to 2 days. Allowing us to process ~6x the number of applicants.
- Sprint planning, bug capture/prioritisation and plotting the roadmap across our apps shaping the direction of our tech stack.
- Adopted Agile methodologies for my own team such as daily stand-ups and weekly retros. The
  weekly retros allowed us to objectively look at how we worked which was crucial to being able to
  adapt and deal with the consistent fast growth of the company.
- Worked across projects communicating specifications, working on designs and feedback between our Development Team and other stakeholders such as our Health Care and Sales teams.

## **Operations Analyst, Lifted**

August 2019 - March 2020

- Created a <u>Python Programme</u> to harness the data we had to start delivering pro-active healthcare. Utilising Numpy, Pandas and Matplotlib.
- Oversaw the day-to-day management of our Carers across London. Starting with 5-10 Carers which grew to 25-30 in these early months. Building strong relationships quickly, getting buy-in to our collective mission.
- Responsible for all company finances covering invoices, expenses and company payroll.

Career break travelling and working in Australia and Japan Operations Associate, Parmenion Capital Partners Investment Consultant, Hargreaves Lansdown Proprietary Trader, Blueprint Capital

June 2018 - August 2019 February 2018 - June 2018 January 2017 - February 2018

December 2014 - November 2016

#### EDUCATION

#### **University of Plymouth**

#### **MSc Finance - Merit (2:1 Equivalent)**

- Advanced calculus such as the Black-Scholes Model, Financial Statement Analysis, Statistics/ Econometrics.
- Thesis that involved processing 15 years of exchange rate data to model the effectiveness of various trading strategies.

# **BSc Economics**

Economics Policy, Global Finances, Economics History, International Trade, Econometrics.

#### HOBBIES

I've always loved playing sport for being part of a bigger team and its competitive aspects. Over time I have played golf, tennis, football and American football.

Outside of programming languages I also like foreign languages and have a 390 day streak of Spanish lessons on Duolingo.